

# **ZUL KAIF** SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PROFILE SUMMARY





zulkaifbangash@gmail.com



**Abu Dhabi - United Arab Emirates** 

A qualified Software Engineer with speciality in Software Development, Web Development and Web Maintenance with 3+ years of experience an excellence skill in analyzing and modifying existing Web apps, as well as Developing, Designing, and Testing End-User applications that match user needs - all using Software Programming languages and different platforms.

#### **SKILLS**

- Superior development skills include OOD, Agile Development, Solutions Architecture, Project Management, and Technical Documentation.
- HTML.
- CSS | SASS | Media Query
- Bootstrap 5.2.1V
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- AJAX & JSON
- React Js
- Typescript
- React Native
- Node.js
- SQL
- Php
- C++
- Python | Web API's
- GitHub
- VS Code
- Structured Query Language (MySQL)
- VBScript
- WordPress
- Photoshop | Illustrator | Figma | Canva
- Website Management | Web Maintenance
- Web Security for the overall Organization
- Software Quality Assurance SQA
  - Exceptional ability to work in the following environments: Java Enterprise Edition, UNIX, Linux, and Windows.
- Excels in systems evaluation to identify system performance indicators and the best course of action to take to improve or correct performance based upon specific system goals.
- Proficiant in Computer Operations and Computer Literacy.

**Tourist Visa** 

• Data Entry with 50+ wpm.

# **CERTIFICATION**

- Data Entry Operator
- Search Engine Optimization SEO
- WordPress
- Digital Marketing

#### **ABOUT ME**

Visa Type:

Nationality: **Pakistan** Passport No: AN5760751 Date Of Birth: 10/06/1994

**Marital Status:** Single

**EDUCATION** 

**Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering** Iqra National University INU - Pakistan

2015 - 2019

**Higher Secondary School Certificate** 

**Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education - Kohat** 

2013 - 2015

**High School Certificate** 

**Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education - Kohat** 2004 - 2013

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software & Web Developer 2020 - 2022 **OZI Technology - Lahore**

- Web developer responsible for end-to-end web app development and creative cloud engineering.
- Develop, upgrade, and maintain advanced financial industry software.
- Coordinate the design and implementation of various applications, including collaboration with project managers, and client representative and development teams.
- Provide mentoring services to junior developers as needed.
- Select projects include the design and development of a flagship financial trading application, a XML content distribution server, and business systems for clients in a variety of industries.
- Created webpages Using WordPress, Reactjs assest clients in Cutting Edge Technology.
- Big achievement built Website for Almadina Real Estate Property
- https://www.almadinamarketing.com/
- Uptate the outdated/old websites into responsive and innovative systems.
- Integrate code changes, test code changes and document code changes.

## Software Developer Intern 2018 - 2020 DruPak.

- Modified existing software to detect and correct errors, improve performance, and upgrade interfaces.
- Consulted with clients regularly regarding projects, proposals, and technical issues that arise during the development process.
- Prepared reports on specifications and activities for each project.
- Collaborated well with other team members to determine the best design specifications and details.
- Get training of Web Development and started work on a website www.ncs.com for a University and completed several Web Apps for corporate level Clients.
- Improved www.inu.com website for our university.
- Developed HTML, CSS, JavaScript and php Web pages for user interaction.

#### **PORTFOLIO**

am Software Engineer with specializing in building exceptional digital experiences. Software developer expert with 3 years of experience in the field, I can quickly create websites using wordpress, but I can also create websites with native coding.

- Strong decision maker, critical thinker, and creative designer with the ability to think around problems to unusual yet highly effective solutions.
- Web Development
- HTMI 5
- CSS | Php
- Structured Query Language (SQL)
- WordPress (With all Themes and Plugins
- Reactis | SaaS and API's
- Software Development
- Python | C++ | C#
- Proficient in Microsoft Suit
- Miscrosoft Word
- Microsoft Access,
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint.
- Experience with email administration.
- Communication and Presentation Skills
- Problem Solving & Time Management.
- Digital Marketing | Social Media Marketing
- Proficiant in Computer Operations and Computer Literacy.
- Leadership & Teamwork Skills
- Communication and Presentation Skills
- Attention to detail | Technology.
- Problem Solving & Time Management.
- Data Entry with 50+ wpm with English, Arabic.
- Ability to meet deadlines
- Interpersonal communication Strong background supporting Windows and OS.
- Experience with email administration.
- Manage the hardware, software and user support.
- Emotional Quotient EQ Skills

# Web and Software Developer OZI Technology - Lahore

- Experimented with multiple iterations during design implementation.
- Wrote extensible and maintainable code as part of a team.
- Excelled in rapidly prototyping new capabilities to confirm project feasibility.
- Designed web applications and maintained content for multiple .NET-based systems.
- Worked as Software Developer on various aspects of projects i,e Develop,maintain, repair and update the client systems.
- Repair, Update the outdated / old websites.
- https://www.almadinamarketing.com
- www.kaiftech.com
- Developed Rapper game for our company.
- www.buraq.pk
- www.kaiftech.com

# Software Developer Intern DruPak - Peshawar

- Completed 6 months Course for Software Development and learnt Technologies such as,
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- php
- React.js
- WordPress
- ¡Query
- Selected for interenship and worked on different projects
- Built an ecommerce webapp to sell products online. Increased company sales by 58%. Increased sale scores by 30%.
- Designed a customer website for a local plant factory.
- http://modernxshop.com/
- www.ncs.com
- www.inu.com
- www.kppsc.pk
- www.tribune.com

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned particular.